<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.sumansedhai.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://www.sumansedhai.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-04-18T16:42:44+00:00</updated><id>https://www.sumansedhai.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A minimalist digital notebook capturing my experiences in cybersecurity, programming, and lifelong learning. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">My CISSP Journey: How I Passed in 100 Questions</title><link href="https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2025/cissp-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My CISSP Journey: How I Passed in 100 Questions"/><published>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2025/cissp-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2025/cissp-journey/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Getting the <strong>CISSP (Certified Information Systems Security Professional)</strong> certification had been on my list for a long time. I bought the study guide nearly two years ago, but like many, I kept pushing it off because I hadn’t booked an exam date. Finally, I decided to stop procrastinating and booked my exam for <strong>December 31, 2025</strong>. From that moment, I started preparing seriously.</p> <p>In this blog post, I’ll share the resources I used, how I structured my preparation, and some insights from my exam experience.</p> <h2 id="resources-i-used">Resources I Used</h2> <p>I took a blended approach to studying — using videos, mind maps, practice questions, and books. Here’s a breakdown of what helped me most:</p> <ol> <li> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ACoAAArK-_sBBlCfhaGFF_3CASSoX1HQhmkVx0o">Prabh Nair</a> - <em>Coffee Shots</em>: Daily short videos that cover CISSP concepts concisely. You can check them out <a href="https://lnkd.in/gB9xwSng">here</a>. Highly recommended for quick revision.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/destination-certification/">Destination Certification Inc.</a> - I followed their mind map videos on YouTube and downloaded the domain summaries from their website. The visual approach made it easy to connect topics.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/professormesser/">Professor Messer</a> - Fantastic resource for clarifying network security concepts. His videos are clear and well-organized.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ACoAACCowTYBGhm3wXYCO2YL4lcTk1-3e6p2OwI">Luke Ahmed 🚀</a> - His strategy on <em>how to think like a manager</em> is something every CISSP aspirant should follow. The exam tests managerial decision-making, not just technical knowledge.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Practice Questions</strong>:</p> <ul> <li>I used <strong>Quantum Exams</strong> extensively.</li> <li>The <strong>Sybex Official Study Guide</strong> practice questions were also a key part of my prep.</li> </ul> </li> <li> <p><strong>Andrew Ramdayal</strong> - His <em>50 CISSP Practice Questions</em> on YouTube were great for getting a feel of exam scenarios.</p> </li> </ol> <h2 id="how-i-studied">How I Studied</h2> <p>I’ve been working in <strong>cybersecurity for almost 6 years</strong>, so many of the concepts were already familiar to me. That definitely helped in grasping advanced topics quickly.</p> <p>I created notes combining key points from all the resources listed above. I’d watch a video or read a chapter summary and immediately jot down essential ideas.</p> <p>For note-taking, I used <strong>Obsidian</strong> — a markdown-based note-taking app — and backed up my notes on <strong>GitHub</strong>. This allowed me to review them from anywhere and keep them organized by domain.</p> <h2 id="exam-experience">Exam Experience</h2> <p>I passed the CISSP exam in <strong>100 questions</strong>, with almost <strong>1 hour left on the clock</strong>. The exam was challenging, and it truly tests your ability to <strong>think like a manager</strong> rather than focusing solely on technical details.</p> <h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2> <p>If you’re preparing for the CISSP, my advice would be:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Book the exam date first</strong>. It creates accountability.</li> <li>Use a mix of video, mind maps, and practice questions.</li> <li>Focus on understanding the <em>why</em> behind every decision.</li> <li>Take consistent notes and revise them regularly.</li> </ul> <p>If you’re a note-taking fan like me, give <strong>Obsidian + GitHub</strong> a try — it made my prep much smoother.</p> <hr/> <p><em>Good luck on your CISSP journey!</em> 🚀</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="cybersecurity"/><category term="certification"/><category term="CISSP"/><category term="certification"/><category term="cybersecurity"/><category term="study-resources"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Light and Shadow - a poem by Suman Sedhai - All Poetry</title><link href="https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2015/light-and-shadow-a-poem-by-suman-sedhai-all-poetry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Light and Shadow - a poem by Suman Sedhai - All Poetry"/><published>2015-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2015/light-and-shadow---a-poem-by-suman-sedhai---all-poetry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2015/light-and-shadow-a-poem-by-suman-sedhai-all-poetry/"><![CDATA[<p> </p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You are not illuminated and dark / always with the pitch black but comes with spark / Crea . Published at the web's largest poetry site.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“What is to be like a poet??” - a poem by Suman Sedhai - All Poetry</title><link href="https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2015/what-is-to-be-like-a-poet-a-poem-by-suman-sedhai-all-poetry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“What is to be like a poet??” - a poem by Suman Sedhai - All Poetry"/><published>2015-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2015/what-is-to-be-like-a-poet---a-poem-by-suman-sedhai---all-poetry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sumansedhai.com/blog/2015/what-is-to-be-like-a-poet-a-poem-by-suman-sedhai-all-poetry/"><![CDATA[<p> </p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[is it just a show off, hiding your hatred? / to hide behind and watch your love departed. . Published at the web's largest poetry site.]]></summary></entry></feed>